Many people believe that ICICI
Prudential Large Cap Mutual Fund
is the market leader in this particular category.  But at the same time,
many people also believe that this
scheme has become totally overdone.  In today's
video, we will analyze various factors about this scheme
and then
decide whether this scheme is really
overpriced or still worth it.  First of all,
we will start with an overview of the fund in
which we will know all the basic details.
So
if you want to make minimum investment in this fund then you can do it from ₹100.  If you want to do
minimum SIP then it is
₹100.  Exit load is 1%.  If
you withdraw your money before 365 days,
you will have to pay 1% exit load or penalty.
Next is its lock-in period.
So there is no lock in period in this scheme.
So you can withdraw your money whenever you want.  No
lock in is going to be yours.
Returns Since Launch: If you
look at it, this is a very old scheme.
Its returns have been around 16%.  And
if we talk about riskometer,
it comes under the very high risk category.
If you look at the benchmark of this particular scheme,
it is Nifty 100 Total Return
Index.  As you know this
is a large cap scheme and where does a large cap scheme
invest?  So
these people invest only in the top 100 listed companies of India.
After this,
if we talk about assets under management, it
is more than Rs 72,000 crore.  The expense ratio
is 0.85%.  I am talking about the direct plan.
But this seems a bit much to me.
0.85 would have been fine if it was around 0.6.
After this,
if we talk about the turnover ratio, it is 16% which is very
low.  Now the fund manager mostly has 100 stocks from
which he
can pick where to invest or
not.  So, I don't expect the turnover ratio to be
high in this category.
But because there
is an active scheme.  If 16% might be consistent for an active scheme,
then it can be a matter of concern because
despite being an active fund, if the
turnover is not high then it becomes a
passive type fund.  Now let us
talk about how well it has performed in the past.
Obviously, past
performance does not guarantee us future performance.
But we will get a little
idea about how consistently this fund has been performing across market sales.
So that we can get an idea about
how much we can depend on this fund
and
how this fund performs in which type of market so that it becomes
easier for you to decide whether this fund is right for you or not.  First of all,
if we look at the 1 year returns, it had given returns of 4.67%.  At the
same time, its
benchmark index had given 2.88%.
It has beaten its benchmark even in 3 years.
It has also beaten in the time frame of 5 years.  It has been done in seven
and also in ten.  It hasn't outperformed this much in 10 years.  The
outperformance is only 1 to 1.5%.  But it has
outperformed.  We cannot ignore this.
If we look at the four time frames of 7 years, 10 years, 5 years
and 3 years, then
this fund comes under the top five schemes in the
large cap category.  This means that
this fund has been a consistent performer
in its category, which is a very good
thing.  Next, we will compare this fund
with its competitors and
see
how well this fund
is performing compared to its competitors.  So its first competitor is SBI
's Large Cap Fund, which comes second
in this category in terms of assets under management.
And if you
look at the performance of both of these for the last 5 years,
you will see that till
approximately July 2023, these schemes were
performing very similar as compared to their
benchmark.
If you look after 2023,
ICICI Pro has started outperforming the scheme a bit
and SBI is still struggling to
beat its benchmark.  You
can see the benchmark chart in green color.  You will get ICICI Pro chart in blue color
and SBI
Large Cap chart in purple color here.
Now if we talk about its next competitor then
it is Nipon India Large
Cap Fund.  This scheme is also quite big
and it has also given very good returns
in the past and if you see, compared to the
large cap funds of SBI and ICICI Pro,
from June 2021 or January 2022 itself, it had
started outperforming the
benchmark as well as the large cap fund of ICICI Pro.
So no doubt Nipon's
India Large Cap Fund is also a good
scheme.  But which one to choose between these two depends
entirely on your personal choice.
You can choose the scheme that you find comfortable according to your risk appetite.
You will also find videos of Nipon India on the channel.
If you want to know about that scheme then
definitely check out that video also.
So compared to ICICI Pro and its
benchmark, Nipon India has totally
beaten it.  You can see it clearly here.
Next, we will talk about its
rolling returns which will tell us
how consistent a performer our large cap fund of ICICI Prudential has been.
So I have taken the rolling returns for the last 5 years.
You can see that compared to its
category, it has given us very good rolling
returns, which is a very
good thing because if a consistent
performer remains in your portfolio,
you will feel a sense of relaxation.  In case
you are not a risky investor and
cannot tolerate volatility.  Now let's
talk about its risk ratios
which will give us an idea about how much
better risk adjusted returns this fund
gives us and secondly how volatile this fund
is so that those who cannot tolerate volatility and do
not want volatile funds in their portfolio can decide
whether this scheme will be right for them or
not.  So standard deviation and beta are
two factors that tell us
how volatile a fund is compared to
its category.  So here is the category
average on the right and on the left you
can see that compared to its category average
this fund is low volatile.  If we
look at beta, it is also showing us low volatility.  The
Sharpe ratio tells us better risk-
adjusted returns.  So the
more the better, so you can see
the category is better than average.  The trainers
ratio is also better than the category average.  And
if we look at Jassens Alpha, it is
almost four times higher than the category.  So
it has generated a much better alpha for you than the category average.
This is the data for the last 3 years.  So
these ratios have been calculated only for the last 3 years.
Now let us look at its portfolio a little more
so that we can get an idea of ​​what
percentage allocation it has currently given to which type of stocks.  So there was a
turnover ratio of 16%.  This means that
not much changes have been made
in the stocks that were in the portfolio from last year to this year.
So you can totally see
what is the percentage of automobiles.  So it's about 8.40.
I am seeing the most portfolio allocation
in banks, which
you will find mostly in large caps, if you
look at other funds as well, then if you want to
read these details then you can read them.
You will also find the top five sector holdings here.
Now the fund manager does
not have much room in the portfolio because if you
look, you will find only 30-40 stocks here
and maximum to maximum there are only
100 stocks in large cap
stocks.  So the
fund manager does not have the space to play that much.  So if
you are investing in a large cap scheme, then in
this case it is
also beating the benchmark.  If you are getting alpha above one or two then it is more than enough.   That's what
I think.  Let
us also discuss a little about fund managers
because how your scheme will perform
depends totally on your fund
managers.  And if you see, this
scheme started around 2008.  And since then, a lot of
fund managers have changed in it.  But
if you look at the last 5 to 6 years,
all these fund managers were managing this fund.
And recently these three fund
managers are common.  So
obviously the fund has performed very well in the last 3 years.
But it may also be a worrying thought
that the fund's assets under
management are continuously increasing
and at such a time it will be a little difficult for the index to outperform the large cap scheme.
So in case, if you
want a scheme which is
a little growing and you
can take a little more risk, then perhaps you will have better
options available for which I have already
made a video on the channel named
Top Five Large Cap Schemes, you
can watch it here and can definitely check it out,
but if you
want stability in your portfolio, then perhaps this fund may be
for you, but
definitely consult your financial advisor, if you
liked the video then definitely like, share and subscribe to the channel, I will meet you
in the next video, till then keep learning, keep
earning